Now that we have a nice method for policy evaluation,
我们已经拥有了完善的策略评估方法
we'll turn our attention to policy improvement.
现在将重点了解如何执行策略完善步骤
So given an action-value function,
给定一个动作值函数
how may we use it to propose a policy.
如何使用它来提出策略？
Is it possible to just copy the algorithm from the dynamic programming case?
可以直接复制动态规划设置中的算法吗？
Maybe we could take the action-value function and
或许可以用动作值函数
construct the corresponding greedy policy.
构建相应的贪婪策略
In other words, for each state we just pick the action with the highest value.
换句话说 在每个状态 我们直接选择值最高的动作
And what do you think, is that approach valid here?
你认为现在该方法有效吗？
The answer is, kind of.
答案是也算有效
If the plan is to combine it with
如果你打算将其与
the policy evaluation algorithm that you just learned about,
刚刚学会的策略评估算法结合使用
we'll need to make some slight amendments.
则需要稍加修改
To see this, let's look at an example.
为此 我们来看一个示例
Say you're an agent and there are two doors in front of you.
假设你是一个智能体 你面前有两扇门
You need to decide which one has more value.
你需要判断哪扇门后面的值更高
Let's see how you might determine this using the ideas behind the Monte Carlo method.
我们来看看如何使用蒙特卡洛方法解决这一问题
At the beginning, you have no reason to favor any door over the other.
一开始 你没有任何理由偏爱某扇门
So let's say you initialize your estimate for the value of each door to zero.
因此假设将每扇门的估算值初始化为 0
And in order to figure out which door to open,
为了判断应该打开哪扇门
let's say you flip a coin,
假设你抛掷了一枚硬币
it comes up tails, and so you open door B.
背面朝上 因此你打开门 B
And when you do that you receive a reward of zero.
这么做时 收到奖励 0
And let's say, for simplicity,
为简单起见
that an episode finishes after a single door is opened.
当打开一扇门时 一个阶段结束
And so in other words,
换句话说
after opening door B,
打开门 B 后
you received a return of zero.
你收到回报 0
So that doesn't change the estimate of
这不会更改值函数的估值
the value function and so it makes sense to just pick a door randomly again.
因此可以再次随机选择一扇门
And so you flip a coin,
你抛掷了一枚硬币
It comes up heads this time,
这次正面朝上
and so you open door A.
打开门 A
When you do this,
这么做时
you get a reward of one.
获得奖励 1
This of course updates the estimate for the value of door A to one.
这样就会将门 A 的估值更新为 1
So now if we act greedily with respect to the value function,
现在如果对值函数进行贪婪的操作
then we open door A again.
再次打开门 A
Say this time, we get a reward of three.
假设这次获得奖励 3
This updates the value of door A to two.
使门 A 的值更新为 2
And so at the next point in time,
在下个时间点
the greedy policy says to pick door A again.
贪婪策略表示再次选择门 A
And say every time we do that we get
每次这么做时
some positive reward and it's always either one or three.
我们都获得正面奖励 始终是 1 或 3
So for all time, we're opening the same door.
因此我们一直都打开相同的门
There's a big problem with this,
这样就存在一个很大的问题
because we never really got a chance to truly explore what's behind the second door.
因为我们始终没有机会看看第二扇门后面的值
For instance, consider the case that the mechanism behind door A is what you'd expect.
例如 假设门 A 后面的机制是你期望的结果
It yields a reward of one or three,
它产生奖励 1 或 3
where both are equally likely but the mechanism behind door B gives a reward of 0 or 100.
二者的概率一样 但是门 B 后面的机制产生奖励 0 或 100
Then that's information that you would have liked to
这是你希望发现的信息
discover but following the greedy policy has prevented you.
但是贪婪策略却阻止你这么做
So the point is, that when we got to a situation early in
问题是 当我们很早就遇到
our investigation where door A seemed more favorable than door B,
门 A 似乎比门 B 更有利的情形时
we really needed to spend more time making sure of that,
我们非常有必要花费更多的时间确认这一点
because our early perceptions were incorrect.
因为一开始的猜测不正确
So instead of constructing that greedy policy,
更好的策略是采用随机性策略
a better policy would be a stochastic one that picked door A with
而不是构建刚才的贪婪策略
95% probability and door B with 5% probability let's say.
例如选择门 A 的概率是 95% 选择门 B 的概率是 5%
Then that's still pretty close to the greedy policy.
依然很接近贪婪策略
So we're still acting pretty optimally.
我们的方法依然很适宜
But there's the added value that if we continue to
但是如果我们继续以很小的概率选择门 B
select door B with some small probability,
就会获得额外的价值
then at some point we're going to see that return of 100.
在某个时刻 我们将看到回报 100
This example motivates how we'll define the Monte Carlo version of policy improvement.
这个示例解释了如何定义蒙特卡洛策略完善算法
Instead of always constructing a greedy policy,
我们不再始终构建贪婪策略
what we'll do instead is construct
而是构建一个随机策略
a stochastic policy that's most likely to pick the greedy action,
以非常高的概率选择贪婪动作
but with some small but non-zero probability picks one of the non-greedy actions instead.
但是以很小的非零概率选择某个非贪婪动作
In this case, you will set some small positive number epsilon where the larger it is,
在这种情况下 你将设置一个很小的正数 ϵ
the more likely you are to pick one of the non-greedy actions,
设置得越大 你就越有可能选择非贪婪动作
and we call this an epsilon-greedy policy.
称之为 epsilon 贪婪算法
Epsilon must be a number between zero and one.
ϵ 必须是 0 到 1 之间的数字
Then with probability one minus epsilon,
智能体以 1-ϵ 的概率
the agent selects the greedy action,
选择贪婪动作
and with probability epsilon,
并以概率 ϵ
it selects any action randomly.
随机选择任何动作
Then as long as epsilon is set to a small number,
只要将 ϵ 设为一个很小的数字
we have a method for constructing a policy that's really close to the greedy policy with
我就能够构建一个非常接近贪婪策略的策略
the added benefit that it doesn't prevent
并且不会阻止智能体
the agent from continuing to explore the range of possibilities.
继续探索其他可能性
So in summary, our algorithm for a Monte Carlo control will look like this,
总之 我们的蒙特卡洛控制算法将如下所示
where I plugged in the fact that
我代入了优化步骤将获得
the improvements step will obtain the Epsilon-greedy policy.
Epsilon 贪婪策略这个结果